你们看见我身后那片泛红的天空了吗
Can you see that area behind me beneath the red-tinted sky?
那就是被遗弃的浣熊市
That is what's left of Raccoon city
军队在这里发射导弹之后
After the military fired a missile at it.
根据未经证实的消息
According to unconfirmed reports
该导弹是原子弹
the missile was allegedly nuclear.
如果这一切是真的 那么这座10万人口的城市...
If this is the case, there's little hope of finding...
将会成为一座死城
any survivors among the city's 100000 inhabitants.
总统先生 请问
Mr. President, what is the connection
保护伞公司和这次事故有什么联系吗?
between umbrella corporation and this incident?
回答结束
No more questions.
导弹的发射和它们有关系吗?
Was the missile launched as a result of this connection?
您能说清楚吗?
Can you shed light on this?
总统已经宣布辞职
The president has announced his resignation.
欧洲保护伞公司的股票持续下跌
Umbrella corporation stock plummeted here in Europe.
此次事件对该商业巨头是沉重的一击...
This dealt a blow to the business giant...
导致商业巨头完全破产
resulting in its complete dissolution.
生化恐怖袭击的受害者数量有增无减...
The estimated number of bioterror victims has skyrocketed...
从成百上千飙升至百万人之多
from hundreds of thousands to over one million.
总统称...
The president announced that the Republic of Bajirib...
由葛兰多将军领导的巴基日耳共和国...
led by General Grande was the latest addition to the list...
最近开始成为赞助恐怖分子的国家之一
of countries that sponsor terrorism.
总统宣布计划使用税款
Announced it plans to put taxpayers' money to work by
拨款10亿给反恐项目
Allocating one billion dollars for an anti-bioterror program
威尔制药公司召开了记者会...
Pharmaceutical company wilpharma issued a press release...
称在有10万多居民的哈瓦德维尔地区...
on establishing a research facility in harvardville...
建立起了研究项目
home to 100000 residents.
我们作了万全的预防措施来确保...
We've taken every precaution to ensure that a catastrophe...
浣熊市遭受的灾难不会重现
such as the one suffered by Raccoon city, is never repeated
参议员东·戴维斯全力支持研究项目的举动...
Inflamed by senator Ron Davis'...
引起了民众的强烈抗议
full support of the new facility
柯蒂斯·米勒博士
Dr. Curtis Miller, a longtime opponent
威尔制药公司研究项目的反对者
of the wilpharma research facility.
被拘捕并指控其妨碍商业行为...
was arrested and charged with obstruction of business...
和恐吓威尔制药的拥护者...
and issuing threats to proponents of Wilpharma's ex...
我们公司同米勒博士再无瓜葛
Our organization has disassociated itself from Dr. Miller.
人权组织土地救援部
The human rights organization terra-save has demanded...
要求威尔制药公司公布
Wilpharma release the results of
在印度的试验结果
their tests conducted in India
威尔制药股价的暴跌
Wilpharma stock fell sharply
引起了土地救援部的...
as a result of scathing accusations...
强烈愤慨
hurled at them by terra-save.
威尔制药滚蛋
Wilpharma must go.
《生化危机：恶化》
威尔制药滚蛋
Wilpharma must go.
我们抗议 威尔制药滚...
We say no. wilpharma must...
土地救援成员在哈瓦德维尔机场前
Members of terra-save lie in wait here
伺机等候
in front of Harvardville Airport
戴维斯参议员的到来
in anticipation of senator Davis' imminent arrival.
土地救援的成员期望
The group hopes to confront the politician who
能与出席国家药品会议的政客有所抗衡
will be attending the national pharmaceutical conference.
来自新泽西纽瓦克的349号航班...
Now arriving in gate 32A...
于32A号口出闸
Flight 349 from Newark. New Jersey.
前往西尔弗斯坦布鲁克的乘客听到广播后请到7号口检票
Will a Brock Silverstein please report to gate 7?
前往西尔弗斯坦布鲁克的到7号口检票
Brock Silverstein to gate 7.
来自哥伦布的89号航班已到达17号出口
Flight 89 from Columbus has just arrived at gate 17.
请即将出发的乘客注意
For those waiting to depart
飞机稍作清理后
It'll just take a minute to de-board...
即将起飞
and turn the plane around.
好久不见了
It's been ages.
你气色不错
You look great.
你看起来可很憔悴啊
You look tired.
都怪我的新男友 他都不让我睡觉
Blame my new boyfriend  he won't let me get any sleep.
男朋友? 是那个你说的
Boyfriend, huh? is that what
在世界卫生组织做事的人吗?
You're calling the W.H.O. report now?
是食品药品管理局啦
FDA, actually.
阿姨  我好累啊
Aunt. I'm tired.
真对不起啊
Yes. I'm sorry.
待在这儿
Stay here and I'll bring the limousine around
我尽快把车叫来
as quickly as I can.
你能帮我照看一下瑞尼吗?
Will you watch Rani for a minute?
- 当然  - 我一会儿就回来
- Sure thing.  - I'll be right back.
那好吧 我们来互相认识一下
Well, we should introduce ourselves.
我叫克莱尔·雷德菲尔
I'm Claire Redfield.
- 你可以叫我克莱尔  - 我是瑞尼
- You can call me Claire.  - I'm Rani.
很高兴见到你 瑞尼 你的名字很好听
Nice to meet you. Rani. that's a pretty name.
打扰一下 先生 你还好吗?
Excuse me. Sir, are you feeling all right?
你要喝点水吗?
Would you like me to bring you some water?
我急着去见威尔制药的弗雷德里克·道因
It's urgent I reach Frederic Downing from Wilpharma.
情况紧急
Emergency.
我们抗议 威尔制药滚蛋
We say no. Wilpharma must go.
你也在土地救援部做事吗?
Do you work for terra-save too?
是的 和你阿姨一样
Yep. just like your aunt.
我喜欢土地救援部的每个人
I like everybody from terra-save
因为他们都很酷
Because they're all pretty cool.
你是打坏蛋的 对吗?
You fight bad guys, right?
- 坏蛋?  - 像他这样的
- Bad guys?  - Like him.
戴维斯参议员
Senator Davis you serve as
您作为威尔制药公司的特别顾问
a special advisor for Wilpharma corporation.
在观看了他们最新的人体试验之后...
After viewing photos of their latest human test subjects...
有什么想法呢?
what are your thoughts?
也许 印度的万圣节
That Halloween is celebrated earlier
比美国来得要早
in India than in the U.S. maybe?
是吗? 我真的不明白美国人的幽默
Really? I simply don't understand American humor.
抱歉 我并不是说...
Apologies. I didn't mean to...
别担心 我懂的
Don't worry about it. I can relate.
你们俩也在等人吗?
Are you two waiting for someone as well?
是啊
Yeah.
我看是疯人院把病人全给放出来了吧
Well. I think the asylum let the patients out for the day.
外面的世界真疯狂
It's a bit crazy outside.
你说的还算轻的
That's an understatement.
戴维斯参议员给哈瓦德维尔带来的...
The air dome research facility isn't the only thing...
并不只是空气室研究项目
senator Davis brought to Harvardville.
它更像是发了疯的马戏团来到了城里
It's like the wacko circus hit town.
我...
Well. I...
我不能再等了 我去拦的士了
I'm weary of waiting. I'm going to grab a taxi.
祝你们愉快 女士们
Good day, ladies.
是哪个王八蛋泄露了我要来的消息?
Who the hell let it leak out that I was coming?
现在这些该死的煽动者
Now those damned agitators
在外面搞了那么多麻烦
are out there stirring up trouble.
我可不想这样 让他们滚蛋
I don't need this. get them out of here.
这他们是什么玩意儿?
What tar pit did this crap ooze out of?
对不起 我给您换一杯
I'm sorry. I'll get you another.
我不管怎么做 把他们赶掉就行
I don't care what it takes, just get rid of them now.
如果有必要 就逮捕他们
Arrest them if you have to.
可是 先生 我们没有理由逮捕他们
But. Sir, we don't have any grounds for arrest.
他们没做犯法的事情
They haven't done anything illegal yet.
参议员 我可以提个建议吗?
Senator, may I make a suggestion?
我们可以从大门偷偷的溜出去
We could slip out through the regular entrance.
没人会料到的 所以他们也不会注意我们
No one would expect that, so the crowd won't notice us.
什么? 见鬼 我才不要
What? hell, no.
我可是被推选的行政官员
I am an elected official.
我才不会像丧家之犬一样偷偷的溜出去
I will not skulk out of here like some whipped dog.
你让那群暴乱份子滚出去
Now. I won't budge from this spot
不然我就不走了
Until you get that swarm of vermin out of the building.
是那个坏蛋 克莱尔
The bad guy. Claire.
是他 是我们在电视上看到的那个坏蛋
It's him. the bad guy we saw on TV.
戴维斯参议员 能问您一句吗?
Senator Davis. can I have another word?
- 不行  - 请说两句 参议员 说两句吧
- You cannot.  - Please, senator. please.
就问一个问题 您为什么...?
Just one more question. why would you...?
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is this?
瑞尼 在这儿等我 好吗?
Rani, wait here, okay?
是别人让你扮成这样的
Did someone put you up to this
还是你自己天才的想法?
Or is this stupid costume your brilliant idea?
好吧 天才 你有话要说...
Okay, genius, you got something to say...
让他从我面前滚开
get it off your chest and move on.
闹够了吧
This is too much.
夫人 您有参与吗?
Ma'am, are you involved in this?
从某种意义上说 有间接参与吧
Indirectly, in a manner of speaking.
那么 从某种意义上说...
Then, in a manner of speaking...
您也得和我走一趟了
you're coming with me too.
- 不行 请等一会儿  - 警长
- No, wait just a minute.  - Chief.
我的天啊
Oh  my god.
这是怎么回事?
What's going on here?
退后
Stand back.
走 走 走 快离开这里
Move, move, move. out of the way.
退后
Stand back.
离他远一点
Move away from him now.
该死
Damn.
太迟了 他已经死了
Too late. he's dead.
我们快点离开这鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
快跑
Run.
快走 快点
Get away. hurry.
等等 你要去哪儿?
Hey, wait. where are you going?
从哈瓦德维尔机场为您发来的现场报道
Reporting live from Harvardville Airport.
一名威尔制药公司的反对者...
A protestor demonstrating against Wilpharma corporation...
袭击了一名警员 据称该警员已殉职
attacked and supposedly killed a police officer.
但现在 那名警员又以类似的方式...
But now, that same officer has just attacked...
袭击了东·戴维斯参议员的保镖
senator Ron Davis' bodyguard in a similar manner.
爱迪 你为什么停下来了? 怎么...?
Eddie, why did you stop rolling? wha...?
瑞尼
Rani.
Rani!
瑞尼
柯蒂斯·米勒
Curtis Miller.
瑞尼?
Rani?
请帮帮我
Please. help me.
所有在候机厅的人请注意
Attention all persons inside the terminal.
立即疏散 离开大厅
Evacuate the building immediately.
重复一次 立即疏散 离开大厅
Repeat, evacuate the terminal immediately.
这不是演习 所有的出口已开通
This is not a drill. use all exits.
所有人立即疏散 离开大厅
Everyone evacuate the terminal building immediately.
不
No.
不可能
No way.
这一切都不是真的
This can't be happening.
当地警方将整个机场封锁为一级防范区域...
Local police have secured the entire airport in a lockdown...
所有入口区域被封锁
and access into the area is blocked.
官方并未公开详细情况
Authorities are not releasing details
现在
and we have very little information.
我们所得到的信息非常有限
at this time.
然后 据未确实的报道称...
However, according to unsubstantiated reports...
在机场的某候机厅内
a bioterror event has occurred
发生了生化恐怖袭击
in one of the airport terminals.
东·戴维斯参议员
Senator Ron Davis is among those
也被滞留在了机场内
Who are confined within the airport.
现在 他的情况...
At present, his condition...
帮我一把
Give me a hand.
我要回家
I want to go home.
我不懂你们为什么不让我离开
I don't understand why you won't let me leave.
为什么我们不能进行营救?
Why can't we stage rescue operations?
求您了 警长 跟您的上司谈一下吧
Please. Chief. you've gotta talk to your higher-ups.
您也听见911的呼叫了 不是吗?
You heard the 911 call, didn't you?
拜托了 求你了
Come on, please.
该死
Damn it.
怎么了? 又给傻逼警长打电话了?
What's the matter? Chief jackass again?
现在什么情况?
What's the status of the site?
整个机场都被封锁了
Well, the entire airport is completely blockaded now.
我们被2个人袭击了
We were attacked by two people
他们应该是刚被感染的
that I believe were recently infected.
不过别担心
But don't worry.
我们抓住了他们 把他们锁在了特遣部队的车里
We caught them and locked them up in a task-force vehicle.
尽管如此 把被感染的人关起来...
But even so, becoming infected by being bitten...
就像是恐怖电影里的情节
It's like something out of a horror movie.
这些人从坟墓里慢慢爬出来
Those creatures rising up out of their graves.
拜托 开个玩笑嘛 不过说真的...
Come on. I'm just kidding. But seriously...
你觉得是威尔制药公司的药物
do you think this Wilpharma drug
致使他们这样的吗?
has something to do with all this?
不知道
I don't know.
既然这之间有联系 就无法制止...
Even if there is a connection, that shouldn't kick off...
一个令人毛骨悚然的瘟疫悄无声息的爆发
a spontaneous outbreak of some creepy-ass plague.
很明显是那恶心的恐怖主义所为
It definitely reeks of terrorism.
这也可以解释为什么国家卫生局
That explains why the State Board of
这么快就送个傻逼到这里了
Health hauled ass to get here so fast.
为什么你觉得政府想极力掩盖这件事?
What do you think the suits are trying to cover up?
如果我知道了 我会受不了的
If I knew that. I'd have a hell of a lot more clout.
白宫派了个特工来接手这个烂摊子
The White House sent a special agent to handle this mess.
他应该快到了
He ought to be here soon.
你可以问问他
You can ask him.
尽管问 但是说实话
Ask all you like, but honestly
这个问题没什么好说的
There's nothing to discuss on that subject.
你他妈是谁啊?
Who the hell are you?
里昂·S·肯尼迪
Leon.S.Kennedy.
你就是那个家伙?
Then you're the one?
这是拨打911的电话之一
This is one of the 911 calls that was made.
- 还有多少幸存者  - 算上我总共4个
- How many are alive?  - Four  including me.
参议员受伤了
One's wounded. the senator.
可以告诉我你的位置吗?
Can you give me your location?
我们在VIP休息厅 抵达厅的最西侧
We're in the VIP lounge, west end of the arrivals lobby.
听着 我不知道我们还能撑多久
Listen. I don't know how long we can hold up.
乘那些东西发现我们之前立即支援 请快一点
Send help now before those things get at us. please hurry.
像是从这里打出的电话
Most likely  that call came from here.
他们就在大气航空公司的VIP休息厅
We believe they're in the VIP lounge for atmos airlines.
目前 机场警察和国家卫生局的人...
Right now, the airport police and State Board of Health...
是第一急救者
are the first responders.
他们彻底关闭了在里面的主要入口...
They've completely shut down the main entrance here...
和两边的入口 这里和这里
and the two side entrances here and here.
没有其他的路通往候机厅了
There are no other routes into the terminal building.
最好的办法是用直升机...
We believe our best bet is to fly in by helicopter...
飞到屋顶 从那里进入
and enter through the roof.
这个小队应该由...
the team should be comprised...
你们俩跟我走 其他人就不用了
I'll take the two of you. no one else.
什么? 为什么?
What? Why?
我可不想冒增加感染人数的危险
Because I don't care to risk increasing the number of infectees.
你也不想被迫向你的朋友开枪 对吧?
You don't want to be forced to shoot your friends, do you?
等会儿 你不是说真的吧
Hey. hey. Hold on a second. You can't be serious.
他以为他是谁啊? 长的都不像军人
Who does this guy think he is? He doesn't look military.
他是来处理这场灾难的特工
He's the special agent assigned to this incident.
我们拭目以待吧
Let's just see what he can do.
感染病毒者会攻击别人...
Those infected with this virus will attack other people...
任何人 无一例外
anyone, without exception.
被咬的人受到感染 再去攻击别人
The people that are bitten become infected and go on to attack others.
只有摧毁感染者脑部 才能阻止病毒传染
The only way to stop the infection is to destroy the infectees' brains.
摧毁他们的脑部?
Destroy their brains?
射击他们的头部
Shoot them in the head.
我们到了
We're here.
僵尸们的丧歌
The song of the infected.
等等
Wait.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
放松点儿
Take it easy.
救援马上就到
Help is on the way.
你这是干吗?
What the hell are you doing?
你自己看看
Look.
不许动 不然我开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot.
这怎么可能
That's impossible.
安琪拉
Angela.
你们喜欢吗?
You like that, huh?
- 想尝点枪子? 别管我  - 够了 停下
- You want some of this? get off.  - Stop, enough.
来吧 来吧
Yeah, come on. yeah!
- 快停下 够了  - 别管我
- That's enough. Stop.  - Get off.
变态
Freaks.
怎么回事 伙计?
What the hell, man?
我打到她了 没理由啊
I shot her point blank. there's no way I could've missed her.
告诉过你 只有射击头部才可以毙命
I told you. the only way to stop them is to shoot them in the head.
这是他们唯一的软肋
It's their only vulnerable spot.
切记 否则就是浪费时间和子弹
Don't forget it, otherwise you'll waste time and ammunition.
这么做 带来的就是死亡
And that can prove to be fatal.
走吧
Let's go.
- 有枪声  - 他们派救援过来了
- Those were gunshots.  - They sent help.
我们能离开这里了
We're gonna get out of here.
你们真该谢谢我
You should thank me.
要不是知道我在这儿 他们才不会管你们死活呢
If you hadn't told them I was here, they would've ignored your call.
想想你的秘书把你丢在这里送死...
You might want to stick your ego up your ass...
你还能自我感觉良好
considering your own secretary left you here to die.
什么声音?
What was that?
有人没受到感染
Someone who isn't infected.
我们得帮忙
We have to help.
太迟了 我们帮不上什么
It's too late. there's nothing we can do.
没错 如果你要去 那我跟着你
That's right. I mean if you, then I leave too.
不 克莱尔 别走
No. Claire, don't go.
我爸爸走时也是这么说的
When my father left  he said the same thing.
他说要去帮妈妈...
He said he was going to go help my mother...
结果他们俩都没有回来
but he didn't come back  and neither did she.
如果你走了 你也不会回来的
And if you leave, you won't come back either.
没事的
It's okay.
我会回来的
I am gonna come back.
- 我保证  - 真的?
- I promise.  - Really?
顺便问一下 我们这儿有什么东西可以当武器吗?
By the way, do we have anything here that can be used as a weapon?
真没想到这也能派上用场
Never saw this coming.
有人吗?
Is there anyone there?
没回答 可不是好兆头
No answer. Never a good sign.
趴下
Get down.
里昂
Leon.
- 你怎么在这儿?  - 我还想问你呢
- What are you doing here?  - I could ask you the same thing.
你就是那个秘书?
You're the one?
就这么点儿人?
Is this it?
- 没错  - 增援呢?
- Yup.  - Reinforcements?
没有 我们靠自己出去
None. We're getting out alone.
指望你有个什么计划是不是太奢望了?
Is it too much to hope you at least have some sort of a plan?
- 我们从大厅直接穿出去  - 你有病啊?
- We're gonna run across the lobby.  - Are you insane?
大厅里爬满了怪物
The lobby is crawling with those creatures.
那里最为开阔
It's also the widest area.
绕远路太危险了
It's too dangerous to take the long way around.
他说的没错
He's right.
他们行动迟缓 能冲过去
They aren't fast. We can get by them.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
什么时候民间组织成员...
And since when did the NGO member...
对这些东西也这么专业了?
become such an authority on the subject?
她是浣熊市少有的幸存者之一
She's one of the rare survivors of Raccoon city.
她比这里任何一个人对这噩梦般的遭遇...
She has more experience with this kind of hellish nightmare...
更有发言权
than anyone else here.
浣熊市不就是那个...?
Hey, raccoon city, isn't that where the...?
是的
Yes.
跟上
Run.
跟上我 瑞尼
Keep up with me. Rani.
- 走  - 多谢
- Go.  - Thanks.
参议员
Senator.
长官
Sir.
格雷格
Greg.
见鬼
Shit.
他被咬了
He got bit.
妈的 他被咬了
He damn well got bit.
退后
Stay back.
你们走吧
Go on without me.
- 格雷格 等等  - 格雷格
- Greg. Wait.  - Greg.
你来搞定?
You got this?
格雷格
Greg.
格雷格 不要
Greg. no.
格雷格
Greg.
Greg!
你还好吗?
You okay?
我看起来能好到哪里去?
Do I look like I'm okay?
我们要从这里出去?
Are we going to make it out of here?
我们仔细分析过 这里直通出口
We have a clear view and a straight path to the exit.
尽可能的都出去...
We'll take out as many as we can...
拼命的跑出去
and run like hell.
安琪拉 掩护我
Angela, back me up.
明白
Got it.
不能再快点干掉他们吗?
Can't you get rid of them any faster?
他们开始向这里集聚了
They're starting to gather over here.
我们跑不出去了 是不是?
We're not gonna make it out, are we?
越来越难了
It's getting tough.
我们马上出发
We gotta go.
瑞尼
Rani.
克莱尔
Claire.
你没事吧?
You all right?
够悬的
Barely.
- 瑞尼 没事吗?  - 克莱尔
- Rani, are you okay?  - Claire.
我们走吧
Let's go.
谢谢
Thank you.
参议员跑哪里去了?
Where's the senator?
终于出来了
Finally.
我出来了
I'm over here.
光 朝着有光的地方跑
The light. run towards the light.
把这里包围起来 行动
Get that perimeter set up. move.
别站着不动 行动起来
Don't stand there, man. set it up.
快 快 开火
Move in, move in. open fire.
- 把他们毙了 全都毙了  - 快
- Light them up, boys. light them up.  - Get a move on.
快 快
Move, move.
瑞尼
Rani!
Rani.
阿姨
Aunt.
- 阿姨  - 我的天啊 你还好吗
- Aunt.  - Oh  my god. You're all right.
我吓死了
I was so scared.
阿姨
Aunt.
到处都是怪物
They were everywhere.
- 我以为再也看不到你了  - 真受不了小孩子
- I didn't think I would see you again.  - I can't stand kids.
整天在那里唧唧歪歪的
They're a real pain in the ass.
我可怜的宝贝
Oh  my poor darling.
混蛋
Bastard.
就是因为你 那个小女孩的余生里...
That girl will have nightmares...
都会有恶梦陪伴
for the rest of her life because of you.
放开我 把她给我 求求你了
Let me go. give her to me. please.
我来吧 我来吧
I got it. I got it.
克莱尔
Claire.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我了解 宝贝 但是她没事 真的
Oh, honey. I know. But she's fine, really.
只是需要点时间
We just have to wait.
没问题
No problem.
我来搞定
I'll take care of it.
最坏的情况下可以用这个
We can use that in the worst-case scenario.
我没打算让威尔制药...
I have no intention of letting Wilpharma...
像个英雄那样结束
end up looking like a savior.
(威尔制药)
哈尼根 我来报告情况
Hey  Hunnigan. I'm reporting in.
我已经听说了
I already heard.
关键时刻海军抵达 挽救了一切
The marines landed in the nick of time and saved the day.
听到这消息 你不知道我有多欣慰
I can't tell you how relieved I am.
你能拿到授权真不可思议
I'm amazed and impressed you got authorization for that.
- 你肯定用了些私人关系  - 没错 我有些人脉
- You must have pulled a few strings.  - Yes. well. I have my resources.
我从陆军传染病医学研究所得到确认...
After I received confirmation from usamriid...
这次袭击的病毒的确是T病毒...
that the virus used in this attack was indeed the T-virus...
我向总统呈交了方案
I submitted a plan to the President.
作为紧急法案发布实施
He pushed it through as a special emergency act.
每个参加战斗的海军都注射疫苗了
Every marine involved in the assault was vaccinated.
- 恐怖分子提了什么条件?  - 还没有
- Have the terrorists made demands?  - No, not yet.
几分钟前联邦调查局在洛杉矶...
But the FBI captured a member of general grande's army...
逮捕了一个葛兰多军队的军人
in Los Angeles just moments ago.
审讯他的时候可能会得到些信息...
When we interrogate him, he might give us some information...
建立起...
that'll establish a link...
这起恐怖袭击和印度那次的联系
between this terrorist attack and the one in india.
也许还能得到...
Maybe we'll dig up a lead on the where abouts...
一些前保护伞公司职员的信息
of former umbrella corporation employees.
肯定是他们把病毒流到黑市上的
They've gotta be the ones peddling the virus on the black market.
这到底是怎么回事?
What the hell is going on?
威尔制药公司的药怎么送到这里来了?
Why are Wilpharma drugs being brought here?
这是疫苗
It's the vaccine.
是你 你在这儿干吗?
You. What are you doing here?
他是威尔制药的首席研究员
He's Wilpharma's head researcher.
我来介绍下 这是弗雷德里克·道因
May I introduce Frederic Downing.
就是他研发了针对病毒的疫苗...
He's the one who developed a vaccine for the virus...
就是你特别熟悉的那种病毒
which you  in particular, are so familiar with.
你是指候机厅里的那些感染者?
You mean the infection in the terminal?
你觉得是威尔制药一手策划的 对吗?
You thought that was wilpharma-engineered, didn't you?
可笑至极
Utterly ridiculous.
预防接种疫苗
An inoculation.
他们研究的是这个 防止疫情蔓延的方法
That's what they've been working on. A way to prevent further outbreaks.
- 但是...  - 克莱尔 是真的
- But...  - Claire, it's true.
- 你知道?  - 是的
- You knew?  - Yes.
只是不知道使用许可审批会如此之快
I didn't think its use would be sanctioned this quickly.
那就在印度进行人体试验...
Then the human testing that took place in India...
掌握了T病毒的恐怖分子发起的袭击
An attack by terrorists that somehow got hold of the T-virus.
葛兰多支持的所有组织成员...
All the members of the group supported by general grande...
都已被感染 我们无法得知内幕
were infected, so we don't know the details.
美国政府得到印度专家的许可...
The U.S. government obtained permission from Indian authorities...
向邻近国家销售T病毒疫苗
to administer the T-virus vaccine to the nearby communities.
威尔制药秘密研制了疫苗
A vaccine secretly developed by Wilpharma.
而且非常成功
It was a success.
感染率下降到了最低
The infection rate was kept as minimal as possible.
你们为什么为了疫苗发起这场袭击?
Why the hell didn't you break out the vaccine for this?
如果在进入前接种疫苗 格雷格就不会...
If we'd been inoculated before we entered the terminal. Greg would...
接种疫苗会让袭击救援人员...
Inoculation would have been entirely possible...
没法帮我们做广告
had terra-save not backed us into an adversarial corner.
能不能通过正常手续...
Had we been able to follow proper procedure...
根据原始计划 疫苗作为国家医药资源
as outlined in the original schedule, the government medical stockpile.
12小时内美国随处可以买到
could have been shipped anywhere in the U.S. within 12 hours.
我的天啊 那么...
Oh, my god. then...
这都是我们的错
it's all our fault.
在那里我可不会跟你吵
I wouldn't argue with you there.
我们最后把事情搞得更糟了
We just ended up making things worse.
不是这样的
That's not true.
这些混帐才用的上那些疫苗
The villains here are the ones who used the virus.
比他们更坏的是那些研发疫苗的人
But worse than them are the ones who made it.
7年前我们的命运被保护伞公司的病毒...
Seven years ago  our lives were changed forever...
永远改写了
by the virus from umbrella corp.
保护伞公司倒闭了...
Umbrella collapsed...
但他们的病毒在继续传播
but their viral legacy continues to spread.
我要把这些病毒从地球上灭绝
I'm gonna scrub this virus from the face of the earth.
你选择的救赎者角色 比我的抗争者要好
You chose the role of rescuer rather than fighter, like me.
你选择了一条你哥哥和我 都无法追随的道路
You chose a path that your brother and I couldn't follow.
你没有错
You weren't wrong.
里昂 谢谢你
Leon, thank you.
快
Hurry.
找些灭火器来
Find some extinguishers.
在气罐爆炸前清空这块地方
Clear the area before the gas tanks blow.
快点 快点
Let's go, let's go.
其他人在哪儿? 快点跟上
Where's the rest of the team? come on.
- 这玩意儿怎么用  - 救命
- How do I use this thing?  - Help.
谁来帮帮我 我被卡住了
Somebody help. I'm stuck.
我来了 我来了
I'm coming, i'm coming.
快点 跟上
Hurry up, come on.
- 发生什么事了?  - 装疫苗的卡车...
- What happened?  - The trucks carrying the vaccine...
还剩下多少疫苗?
How much vaccine is left?
今天带到这儿的疫苗
Everything we brought today
已经是我们从公司的疫苗库里
was all we were able to scrape together
能找到的所有了
from vaccine samples inside the company.
而绝大多数都在刚才的爆炸中丢失了
And most of that has just been lost.
那研发数据呢?
Where's the manufacturing data?
- 难道你认为他们也在找数据吗  - 有可能吗?
- You think they're after the data too?  - Could it be?
为什么你不告诉我们 他们的要求是什么?
Why don't you tell us what their demands are already?
如果你不愿意说 我可以直接去问总统
If you don't wanna talk I'll just go directly to the President.
真相
The truth.
真相?
Truth?
他们要事实的真相
They demand the truth.
由保护伞公司研制的
The viral weapon from which umbrella
T病毒已经变异了
corporation's T-virus was derived.
他们想还每一个被美国政府
They wanna reveal everyone
牵涉进来的人以清白
from the U.S. government who was involved.
政府究竟做过些什么?
Was the government really involved?
证据已经同浣熊市一起灰飞烟灭了
The proof went up in smoke with Raccoon city.
等等 真相并没消失
Wait a minute. the truth didn't disappear.
- 根本就没有什么证据  - 那你就去向恐怖分子们解释吧
- There never was any.  - Convince the terrorists of that.
如果他们得不到想要的东西 会发生什么?
If they don't get that information, what will happen?
他们会在全美国
They'll disperse the T-virus
所有的居民区散播T病毒
in every populated area in the u.s.
最后期限是午夜
The deadline is midnight.
只剩下4个小时了
That's only four hours from now.
而且现在也没有疫苗了
And there's no vaccine left.
难道我们就不能找出那些恐怖分子是些什么人吗?
Can we find out who the terrorists are?
我找到他们其中一人的线索
I have a clue as to the identity of one of them.
就在首批被感染者
Right after the first infected victims
出现在机场候机厅的时候...
appeared in the airport terminal...
我注意到一个在大厅的男人 他的名字叫柯蒂斯·米勒
I noticed a man in the lobby. His name is Curtis Miller.
我知道他 他是那些反对建造
I know him. He's one of those bleeding hearts
新的研究设备的顽固分子之一
protesting the construction of the new research facility.
如果恐怖分子的要求仅仅是公开那些...
If the terrorists' demands are the release of information...
发生在浣熊市的真相...
on what really happened in raccoon city...
- ...那他可能...  - 不可能
- ...Then he might...  - It can't be.
柯蒂斯·米勒是...
Curtis Miller is...
我的哥哥
my older brother.
我哥哥是不会做这种事的
My brother wouldn't do something like this.
他曾因威胁威尔制药被捕
He was arrested for threatening Wilpharma.
他仅仅是要求真相被公之于众
He just demanded information be made public.
不幸的是 其他人并不这样看
Unfortunately, the rest of the world doesn't see it that way.
如果象你所说的 他不是恐怖分子
If you claim he's not a terrorist
为什么你不把他带到这儿 让他自己说? 现在就去
Why don't you bring him here to explain himself? Now.
你觉得带这么多家伙
You're sure packing a lot of hardware
去见你哥哥合适吗
Just to go see your brother.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
去办公室看看疫苗的研发数据还在不在
I'm going to the office and check on the development data.
我能帮上什么忙吗? 别担心
Can I help you with something? Don't worry.
我并不是想潜入你们公司
I'm not scheming to infiltrate your organization
去干什么不法的勾当
for my own devious purposes.
恐怕只有一件事你能做
I'm afraid there's only one thing you can do.
同我一道喝下午茶
Join me for a late afternoon tea.
好了 感觉舒服吗?
There you are. Comfortable?
有人作伴真是件不错的事
It'll be nice to have some company.
这是到柯蒂斯家去的路
This is the road to Curtis' home.
3年了 我没有听到过哥哥的任何消息
I haven't heard a word from Curtis in three years.
在浣熊市事件中他失去了自己的妻儿
He lost his wife and child in the Raccoon city tragedy.
真奇怪 居然不认我的卡
That's odd. It won't accept my card.
- 以前发生过这种事吗?  - 没有 这还是第一次
- Has that happened before?  - No. This is the first time.
(错误)
看来得用主控密码才行
I'll have to use the master code.
(解锁)
我们正在进入一个空气室
We're entering an air dome.
屋顶是由内部和外部的
The roof is supported by creating a difference
气压差支撑起来的
between the exterior and interior air pressure.
系统的危险程度由每个部门中
The danger levels in this facility are assigned
所植入的微生物来衡定
according to the microbes that are handled in each section.
从右边开始 危险程度从1上升到4
From the right, the levels ascend from 1 to 4.
数字越大 危险程度越高
The higher the number, the higher the danger level.
不过请放心
Rest assured, however, that there are
这儿有严格的安全措施
stringent safety measures in place
预防突如其来的安全事件
in the unlikely event a problem occurs.
如果在浣熊市的废墟上有任何动静
If anything positive rose from the ashes of Raccoon city
它的保安及防御系统
It's that security and safeguard
将会自动提升等级
standards have been elevated
来防止灾难发生
In order to avert any future calamities.
这个0指的是什么意思?
What about this zero area?
那代表研究员的办公室
That contains researchers' offices
以及会议室等等
Meeting rooms and the like.
也就是我们待会儿要去的地方
That's where we're headed next.
这儿可不是天堂
This isn't paradise.
这就是我需要你帮我做的事
This is what you came to assist me with.
谢谢
Thank you.
闻起来不错
Smells delicious.
- 你在做什么?  - 检查研发数据
- What are you doing?  - Checking on the development data.
(东·戴维斯)
- 你好 参议员先生  - 我猜你现在一定在那儿了
- Yes, senator.  - I figured you must be there by now.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
为什么把那个女人带过去?
Why did you bring that woman there?
你该不会是下不了手吧 对吗?
You're not feeling sorry for her, are you?
这可不象你的作风
That's not like you.
难道你不明白吗? 这是我们的机会
Don't you understand? This is our chance.
是的 我明白
Yes. I know.
好的
Yes.
他说什么了?
What did he say?
没什么事 我向你保证
Nothing of any consequence. I assure you.
他说了些什么 对吗?
He said something to you, didn't he?
他警告我不要给你看任何东西
He warned me not to let you see anything.
如果我看见什么不该看的 会有什么后果吗?
Would it cause trouble if I saw something in particular?
没有
No.
在我刚入警队的时候
When I started out as a rookie cop.
奉命去营救一个被困在
I responded to a call about a small child
洪水之中的小沙丘
That was stranded on a sandbank
上面的小男孩儿
in the middle of a flooding river.
我激动的跳入水中
I impulsively jumped into the river.
但接下来我知道的...
The next thing I knew...
就是我躺在医院的床上 意识模糊不清
I was waking up in a hospital bed  bleary and disoriented.
后来他们告诉我
They informed me afterward
我救下了那个小孩
that I had saved the child.
但3个SRT的警官却
But three S.R.T. members were injured
为弥补我捅下的篓子而受伤
while fishing my sorry butt out of the water.
说到沮丧 当时的我简直万念俱灰
Talk about depressed. I felt lower than dirt.
脑海中总是在想 我怎能让他人来承担自己犯下的过错?
What was I thinking, putting others in harm's way like that?
更别提我也差点送命
Not to mention that I could've been killed too.
但柯蒂斯对我说的话
But then Curtis said something
让我停止了为自己愚蠢行为的哭泣
That made me stop beating myself up.
"如果你不试着去拯救每一个生命"
"If you don't try to save one life
"那你就拯救不了任何人"
You'll never save any."
但最后
In the end
他却在自己的信念中迷失
His own words came back to haunt him.
让我过去 让我过去
Let me through. Let me through.
有一些东西 但戴维斯不想让人知道
There is something, but Davis wants it to remain hidden.
这是G病毒
This is the G-virus.
你们这儿有这东西?
You have that here?
这是最高机密 连公司里的人也不知道
It remains a secret even within the company.
甚至政府机构也不知道它的存在
The government affiliates don't know about it either.
它是通过特殊手段得来的
It was obtained through special means.
我们和参议员也不过是为了
A group with which neither we nor someone
共同的利益才联合起来的
in the senator's position can be associated.
你是从黑市上得到这东西的
You got it on the black market.
你打算拿G病毒做什么?
What did you plan on doing with the G-virus?
制造疫苗 但就算是参议员
Create a vaccine. But even the senator
也难以向政府
Couldn't adequately express
陈述此项目的潜在威胁
The threat posed to the government.
这个从初始就被定义为
The plans were shelved
级别4的项目就这样被搁置了
and it remains in level 4 ever since.
参议员是决定炸毁浣熊市的
The senator is a member of the committee
策划者之一
That decided to bomb Raccoon city.
我得把这个告诉里昂
I've gotta tell Leon.
等等 不 我...
Wait, no. I...
如果你这么做了 那我该怎么办?
If you do that, what's going to happen to me?
你告诉我这些的时候
You didn't seem worried about that
没看到你脸上有什么担心的表情
When you were telling me everything.
好像... 好像...
Looks like... looks like...
服务器出了点问题
There's something wrong with the server.
我得去阻止柯蒂斯
I'm going to stop Curtis.
克莱尔 怎么了
Claire. What's wrong?
里昂 现在马上到威尔制药来
Leon, get over here to Wilpharma right now.
他们有G病毒
They've got the G-virus.
他们本打算想制疫苗 就像T病毒那样
They were gonna make a vaccine like for the T-virus
但戴维斯刚才打电话给弗雷德里克叫他毁掉证据
but Davis just called Frederic and told him to get rid of it.
- 弗雷德里克在那儿吗?  - 他刚出去修服务器了
- Is Frederic there?  - He just went to go fix the server.
或者是去释放病毒了
Or he may have gone to dump the virus.
- 不可能  - 克莱尔?
- Couldn't be.  - Claire?
屋子里有电话打进来
There's a call coming from inside the building.
你等等
Hold on.
- 克莱尔?  - 弗雷德里克? 你在哪儿?
- Claire?  - Frederic? Where are you?
- 在4区  - 为什么?
- In level 4.  - Why?
你说去检查服务器的
You were going to the server room.
我在路上看到可疑的人 于是就跟着他
I saw someone suspicious on my way and followed him.
你必须马上出来 这儿有一个定时炸弹
You need to get out. There's a time bomb.
马上就要爆炸了
It's too late to stop it.
我们将会经历另一场浩劫 如果...
We'll have another biohazard if this thing...
克莱尔? 克莱尔
Claire? Claire!
- 该死的  - 发生什么事了?
- Damn it.  - What's wrong?
我不知道 电话断线了
I don't know. We got cut off.
所有人注意 系统发生错误
Attention all personnel. a system error has occurred.
请停止一切活动 迅速撤离
Terminate all activities immediately and evacuate the dome
直到安全措施重新恢复
Until safe conditions are re-established and verified.
所有人注意 系统发生错误
Attention all personnel. a system error has occurred.
请停止一切活动 迅速撤离
Terminate all activities immediately and evacuate the dome
直到安全措施重新恢复
Until safe conditions are re-established and verified.
所有人注意 系统发生错误
Attention all personnel. a system error has occurred.
请停止一切活动 迅速撤离
Terminate all activities immediately and evacuate the dome
直到安全措施重新恢复
Until safe conditions are re-established and verified.
所有人注意 系统发生错误
Attention all personnel. a system error has occurred.
请停止一切活动 迅速撤离
Terminate all activities and evacuate the dome
直到安全措施重新恢复...
Until safe conditions are re-established...
看起来通道被堵塞了
Looks like sections are blocked.
我们分头行动 在内院碰头
Let's split up. We can meet up again in the inner garden.
- 准备好了?  - 好了
- Ready?  - Ready.
安琪拉
Angela.
你不是一个人
You're not alone.
我与你同在
We're together in this.
我知道
I know.
里昂
Leon.
发生什么事了? 弗雷德里克在哪儿?
What happened? Where's Frederic?
他告诉我在4区
He was telling me about
发现一个定时炸弹 然后...
a time bomb he found in level 4 when...
伤口很深啊 我们离开这儿
A nasty wound. We gotta get out.
我没事 听我说
I'm all right. Listen to me.
柯蒂斯在这儿 我看见他了
Curtis was here. I saw him.
他从4区走出来 而G病毒就保存在4区
He came out of level 4 where the G-virus was kept.
柯蒂斯
Curtis.
安琪拉
Angela.
你受伤了
You're hurt.
你需要看医生
You need medical attention.
- 为什么 柯蒂斯?  - 我无法原谅
- Why. Curtis?  - I couldn't forgive them
他们掩盖了浣熊市事件的事实
for covering up the Raccoon city atrocity.
我拒绝让政府
I refused to let the government
改写他们所认为合适的真相
rewrite the truth as they saw fit.
所以当我知道事实真相的时候 我发誓...
So when I finally learned the truth. I swore...
发誓要将真相公之于众 不管我会因此付出多大代价
I swore I'd make them reveal it, no matter what it took.
柯蒂斯
Curtis.
但他也告诉我...
But he also told me...
我不能让事态进一步的恶化
that I couldn't make things any worse.
即便这是罪有应得
Even if it was deserved
我也不能...
There was no chance of me...
不能让灾难...
Of me causing a recurrence of that horror...
重现在这个生我养我的地方
here in the town where I was born and raised.
这就是为什么他留下了我
That's why he left me.
为什么他要炸掉这个地方
That's why he blew up this place.
等等
Wait.
已经没有什么能阻止它了
Nothing can stop it now.
再过一会儿...
In a moment...
我就能用我的方式...
I'll reveal the irrefutable truth...
向世人展示那无法被辩驳的事实真相
in my own personal way.
而你们 将为成为最早的见证者
And all of you will be the very first witnesses!
顺着这条走廊走下去 在AD-2的电梯处碰头
Go straight down this corridor. Head to elevator AD-2.
它会带你到通往外面的出口
It'll take you to an outside exit.
知道了
Got it.
克莱尔
Claire.
- 小心别送掉自己的小命  - 没问题 你也是
- Try not to get killed.  - Okay, ditto.
行动
Move.
不
No!
停下
Stop.
停止射击 停止射击
Cease fire. cease fire.
目标人物带有攻击性 并且拒捕
The target became aggressive and resisted capture.
建议上头下令对其开火
I deemed it necessary to open fire and issued the order.
消灭目标
The target was terminated.
警告 花园区检测到致命病毒株
A lethal viral strain has been detected in the garden sector.
要求回复
Commencing feedback.
警告 花园区检测到致命病毒株
A lethal viral strain has been detected in the garden sector.
要求回复
Commencing feedback.
- 队长  - 开什么玩笑
- Captain!  - You've gotta be kidding me.
我的部下早把你打得稀巴烂
My men shot the shit out of you.
(中央控制室)
我的腿
My leg.
安琪拉
Angela.
安琪拉 快走开
Angela, get clear.
里昂
Leon.
来人啊
Somebody.
拉我上来
Somebody pull me up.
什么玩意儿?
What is this?
乙醇纯溶液
Anhydrous ethanol.
在对我们消毒吗?
Are we being sterilized?
不是为我们 而是为这大楼
Not us, the building.
大楼5分钟后将会自动炸毁
Incineration will initiate in five minutes.
- 所有的通道已封锁  - 搞什么鬼?
- All exits are now sealed.  - What the hell?
我们还在里面
We're still in here.
把所有人带到中央休息区
Get all survivors to the central rest area now.
快
Move it.
Come on.
警告 所有的通道已封锁
All exits are now sealed.
妈的
Oh, shit.
来
Come on.
- 我们乘下一部  - 行
- We'll catch the next one.  - Right.
我们到...
We'll send it b...
快走
Go!
住手
Stop.
这样我们也会遭殃的
You'll ignite us all.
- 天啊  - 那不可能
- Oh  my god.  - It's impossible.
- 他还活着  - 不 不 不
- He's still alive.  - No, no, no!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
- 里昂  - 安琪拉
- Leon.  - Angela.
- 2分钟后炸毁  - 不
- Incineration in two minutes.  - No!
快逃
Run.
- 什么?  - 快逃
- What?  - Run!
60秒后炸毁
Incineration in 60 seconds.
因为你和他有亲缘关系 他想抓你
It wants you because of your blood connection.
把你当作繁衍的工具
It sees you as a breeding tool.
他不再是你的亲哥哥
That thing isn't your brother anymore.
柯蒂斯已经死了
Curtis is dead.
30秒后炸毁
Incineration in 30 seconds.
跟我来
Come on.
倒数 20 19 18 17秒
Twenty. nineteen. eighteen. seventeen.
16 15 14 13 12秒
Sixteen. fifteen. fourteen. thirteen. twelve.
11 10 9 8秒
Eleven. ten. nine. eight.
7 6 5 4秒
Seven. six. five. four.
3 2 1秒
Three. two. one.
室内花园下坠
Inner gergen falling
天哪 这是怎么回事?
Oh, shit. now what's gonna happen?
不 不 不
No. no, no.
4区下沉系统即将启动
Level 4 submerge system will engage soon.
我们得向上走
We need to go up.
终止系统
Disable the system.
肯定有法子
There's gotta be a way.
我知道这时里昂会怎么做
I know what Leon would do.
这样
Right.
危险警告 确认减压操作
Danger do you want to decrease pressure
好了
There.
压力减少
Pressure decrease
来吧
Come on.
警告 4区下沉系统即将启动
Level 4 submerge system will engage soon.
12 11 10 9 8秒
Twelve. eleven. ten. nine. eight.
7 6 5 4秒
Seven. six. five. four.
3 2 1秒
Three. two. one.
1区下沉系统即将启动
Level 1 submerge system will engage soon.
10 9 8 7 6秒
Ten. nine. eight. seven. six.
5 4 3 2 1秒
Five. four. three. two. one.
柯蒂斯
Curtis.
快跑
Run.
不 不
No. no.
我不想伤害你
I don't wanna hurt you.
别
Please.
不
No.
好吧 柯蒂斯
All right. Curtis.
让我们来个了结
Let's finish this.
警告 0区下沉系统即将启动
Level 0 submerge system will engage soon.
10 9 8 7秒
Ten. nine. eight. seven.
6 5 4秒
Six. five. four.
3 2 1秒
Three. two. one.
系统检测没有病毒之后...
After the system verifies there's no more virus in here...
这个洞口就会关闭
the hole will close.
放开我
Let me go.
天啊 快放手 不然你也会掉下去
Let go of me, damn it, or you'll fall too.
你不能死 你还要销毁那病毒
You can't die. you have to destroy these viruses.
里昂 求求你 别救我
Please. Leon. Don't try to save me.
若不救你 如何拯救世人
If you don't try to save one life, you'll never save any.
难道不是吗 柯蒂斯?
Isn't that right. Curtis?
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
都被录像了
It recorded.
弗雷德里克在哪儿?
Where's Frederic?
死了 疫苗数据 一切销毁
Dead. no vaccine data, no nothing.
跟浣熊市一样
The same as Raccoon city.
什么?
What?
弗雷德里克说的
Frederic said it.
你不能说服国家投资...
You couldn't convince countries to invest...
不充分的G病毒研究
in the development of the insufficiently researched G-virus.
你这是说什么?
What are you talking about?
起初 我还没怀疑与这起恐怖行动有关
At first. I didn't suspect you were connected with this terrorism.
你虽没理由安排自己在发生事故之时
If for no other reason than you were
出现在机场
In the airport when the event occurred.
不过你有引发事件的动机
But you had a motive for causing all this.
股票
Stocks.
由于受到示威影响 威尔制药股票大跌
Wilpharma stock tanked because of our accusations.
你害怕 如此下去...
You were afraid that the situation...
你会重蹈保护伞公司的覆辙
would turn out the same as it did for umbrella corporation.
你要找机会让你的疫苗派上用场
So you needed an excuse to use the vaccine.
慢着
Now, wait a minute.
没错 我是股东
Yes. I'm a stockholder.
这事件后 威尔制药理应重获大众的信任
And Wilpharma should regain the public's faith after this incident.
但我绝不借恐怖主义之手完成这个
But there's no way in hell I would support terrorism to ensure that.
首先 G病毒是什么? 我听都没听过
First of all, what is the G-virus? I've never even heard of it.
只要你一声令下 弗雷德里克就会销毁病毒...
I know you ordered Frederic to dispose of the g-virus...
这我都知道
when you called him.
我只是告诉他 别让你看那么多...
I told him not to show you anything more...
你不该看的机密 仅此而已
than you needed to see, that was it.
我看他还懵然不知
I doubt he knows anything.
里昂
Leon.
据葛兰多将军的通讯员说
General Grande's communication man talked.
看来我们全体 包括议员都被他蒙骗
It seems that all of us, the senator included  were fooled by him.
你说的是谁?
Who are you talking about?
- 弗雷德里克? 你在哪儿?  - 在4区
- Frederic? where are you?  - In level 4.
为什么? 你说去检查服务器的
Why? You said you were going to the server room.
我在路上看到可疑的人 于是就跟着他
I saw someone suspicious on my way there and followed him.
你必须马上出来
You need to get out.
这儿有一个定时炸弹 马上就要爆炸了
There's a time bomb here. It's too late to stop it.
我们将会经历另一场浩劫 如果...
We'll have another biohazard if this thing...
不可能
It can't be.
是我
It's me.
觉得怎样?
What do you think?
是的 遵循你的吩咐
Yes, per your request.
葛兰多将军 现在...
As of now. General Grande...
只有您才拥有...
only you will be in possession...
T病毒及其疫苗
of a set of the T-virus and the T-vaccine.
基于国家想把病毒的事保密...
Nothing would offer greater advantage when negotiating...
用这个去跟他们谈判 最好不过
with a country that wants to keep the existence of this virus a secret.
你不必担心
You needn't worry.
每一步我都有周详的计划...
I've anticipated everything down to the last detail...
甚至连如何逃生我也计算好
including my own escape arrangements.
别忘了...
Don't forget...
G病毒的数据 可是要另外加钱
you owe me extra money for the data on the G-virus.
最后 作为朋友...
and one last thing, As a friend...
听我的劝告 别管G病毒的事
heed my advice and forget about G.
这玩意儿容易突变 很难掌控
The stuff is wickedly volatile, and it can't be controlled.
时间正好
Right on time.
你答应只身前来
You were supposed to come alone.
我只想再看看你的这张脸
I just wanted to see your face one more time.
别动
Don't move.
仅存的疫苗和繁殖数据在我手上
I have the last of the vaccine, and the development data.
这是世上仅存的资料
This is all that remains in the entire world.
其余都销毁了
The rest is gone.
这就对了
Yes, that's right.
你们俩比任何人都更能明白情况...
You two can appreciate the situation better than anyone...
你们还和受感染的人碰过头
after your up-close-and-personal experiences with virus victims.
人类需要这疫苗
Mankind will need this.
慢着 求求你别杀我 我们谈谈
Wait. please. don't shoot me. let's talk.
你是个聪明女人 聪明的女人都喜欢钱
You're a smart woman, and smart women like money.
我能给你钱 我们五五分帐吧
I can make you rich. we'll split everything 50-50.
七三分好了 有三成我就满足
I meant 70-30. I'm happy with 30.
求求你 全给你好了
Please. please, take it all.
别... 别杀我 我求求你们 不要
Don't... don't kill me. I'm begging you. please, no.
可怜虫不值得我杀
You're too pathetic to kill.
- 所有小队 行动  - 是 长官
- All units, move in.  - Yes  sir.
疑犯已被制服 接受监视
Suspect has been apprehended and is in custody.
弗雷德里克全招了
Frederic confessed everything.
他还给印度恐怖分子提供病毒
He was also the one that provided the t-virus to the terrorists in India.
还装成黑市卖家
He even acted as the black-market broker.
在浣熊城的生化危机爆发前夕...
He stole the T- and G-viruses...
他盗走了T病毒和G病毒 逃离城市
then escaped right before the Raccoon city disaster.
但他知道病毒要和疫苗配套出售才有市场
But Frederic decided he could only sell them as a set with a vaccine.
他消去以前的记录...
So he erased his past...
混进威尔制药公司...
found employment at Wilpharma...
并得到研究设备的任意使用权
and gained unrestricted access to their research facilities.
在制造疫苗的时候...
He had the luxury of searching for potential customers...
他就开始寻觅潜在的客户
while manufacturing the vaccine.
这就是为什么他联系上葛兰多将军
This is how he stumbled upon General Grande.
所有恐怖袭击事件...
The terrorist incidents were demonstrations...
都是为了在将军面前展示
staged for general grande's benefit.
类似于...
Sort of a...
变相的商品宣传
twisted sales pitch.
我的哥哥只是他们的一只棋子
And my brother was just a tool to them.
为人所用
He was used.
这不能免除柯蒂斯的罪过
This doesn't absolve Curtis of what he did.
但至少 我们和他也有相同之处...
But we share something in common with him...
就是热切希望...
and that's his passionate desire...
浣熊市的悲剧不再重演
to prevent any further tragedies like Raccoon city.
得走了
I gotta go.
好
All right.
晚点联系
Catch you later.
里昂
Leon.
有时间的话 我们再一起...
Let's go diving together again...
跳水
sometime.
荣幸之至
Love to.
你们俩啥时候去跳水了?
When did you two go diving?
别打听了
Don't worry about that.
更重要的是 你以后有何打算?
More importantly, what are you up to?
需要载你一程吗?
Need a lift?
我有轿车载
I have a limousine waiting.
克莱尔
Claire.
下次再会的时候...
Next time we bump into each other...
希望能在一个...
let's hope it's some place...
正常点的地方
a little more normal.
当然
Definitely.
下次见
Until next time.
东·戴维斯参议院宣布辞职消息...
Senator Ron Davis announced his resignation...
他被指以大股东身份...
after being accused of insider trading with Wilpharma stock...
幕后操纵威尔制药的股价
a company of which he is a major stockholder.
下面是国际消息
Next in international news
米格·葛兰多将军突然决定...
General Miguel Grande has suddenly decided to participate...
参加中亚裁军计划
in a central asian disarmament conference.
但当中因由 无从得知
But the real motivation behind his participation is not yet known.
此举获得政府的支持...
Government sources seem to be optimistic about the turnaround...
声称这可以减缓经济衰退...
and say that it is to alleviate economic blockades...
但有谣传...
while rumors state that it is because...
他被削去研究生物武器的权力
his ability to produce biological weapons has been removed.
(机密档案删除中)